Sama Behfard

Iran, Tehran samabehfard@gmail.com

+989382955500 https://www.linkedin.com/in/samabehfard

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience at ASA and Mapsa. Reduced production bugs and improved software performance. Experienced in migrating applications to microservices, optimizing databases, and integrating APIs. Transitioned 10+ applications to microservices, optimized databases with 20% faster queries.

EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

ASA, Tehran

Jan 2023 - PRESENT

- Achieved honorable acceptance from ASA within 12 months and subsequently integrated into the main ASA company.
- Developed automated tests using the TDD method, resulting in a 30% reduction in production bugs.
- Created and updated technical documentation, improving onboarding time for new team members by 50%.
- Transitioned monolithic application to a microservices architecture, reducing system downtime by 20%.
- Improved response time by 15% by refining third-party calls and usages by 10%.
- Refactored 20+ legacy modules for a cleaner codebase, achieving a 10% improvement in application performance.
- Collaborated with QA teams, reducing the number of high-priority bug incidents by 35% over a 6-month period.
- Bridged communication between 2+ teams, ensuring seamless project coordination.

Software Engineer

NARVAN(ASA's Startup Studio), Tehran

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

- Joined the startup for a cutting-edge financial trading project as part of a 7-member team
- Integrated 5 third-party APIs, enhancing the software's capabilities and broadening the application use-cases.
- Implemented specialized more than 20 financial formulas to the platform's core functionality.

- Documented every change to facilitate team collaboration and illustrated sequence diagrams for over 10 algorithms.
- Identified and reported 50+ software bugs, improving system performance and user experience.

Software Engineer Intern

Mapsa, Tehran

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

- Led a team, orchestrating over 30 tasks, to successfully complete the project as the team lead
- Built an e-commerce platform used by 1,000+ mock users.
- Implemented 100,000+ mock test data entries to evaluate platform scalability.
- Achieved a 30% boost in site performance by refining database indexing.
- Aided in refining SQL queries, leading to a 20% reduction in database-related bottlenecks.
- Contributed to the development of 4 new modules, expanding platform features and improving user engagement by 15%.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Software Engineering

Golestan University, Golestan, Gorgan

Sep 2017 - Aug 2021

 Approached every educational endeavor with enthusiasm and a commitment to quality.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Proficient in Python, Java, and JavaScript/TypeScript.
- Technical Expertise: Proficient in data structures and efficient algorithm development.
- **Development Approaches**: Familiar with Agile, emphasizing iterative development.
- **Databases**: Strong experience in database design, SQL query optimization, and also NoSQL Databases like ElasticSearch and Redis.
- Reproducibility Tools: Skilled in using Docker for application environment consistency.
- Operating Systems: Experienced with Linux, especially Ubuntu.
- **Core Competencies**: Logical reasoning, commitment to ongoing learning, and career development.